Florence Rose Papers, 1832-1970
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS AND ACTIVITIES 1921-1968
  - Birth control activities
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (known as the Birth Control Federation of America from 1938-Mar 1942)
      - Events
        - "Creating the World of Tomorrow" dinner: correspondence and draft invitations, Apr 1939 (Box 25, Folder 11)
        - Fiftieth Anniversary conferences: programs, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 12)
        - "Race Building in a Democracy" symposium: speeches, 23-25 Jan, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 13)
        - Southern Conference on Tomorrow's Children: correspondence and program, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 14)
        - "Strengthening Our Population for National Defense" dinner: program and seating lists, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 15)
        - Staff Institute: program, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 16)
        - Twenty-fifth Anniversary of the Founding of the First Birth Control Clinic in America: lists, plans, publicity, speeches, and congratulatory messages, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 17)
        - White House Luncheon Meeting: memoranda and reports, 1941 and 1966 (Box 25, Folder 18)
        - Workshop: minutes and program, 1942, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - Fundraising lists, 1939-40 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - Legal issues: correspondence, memoranda, statements, and summaries, 1936-40 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Memoranda, 1939-43, undated (Box 25, Folder 23-25)
      - Programs
        - Education: educational materials, memoranda, and project outline, 1941-43, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
        - Public health: correspondence, memoranda, questionnaires, and schedules, 1941, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Proposals, 1943-44 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Publications
        - Drafts, 1939, undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
        - Articles and lists, 1938-41, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
        - Journal: Human Fertility, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - Newsletters
          - News Exchange, 1944-46 (Box 26, Folder 7)
          - Information Service, 1940-41 (Box 26, Folder 8)
          - Planned Parenthood News, 1948-56 (Box 26, Folder 9)
          - Planned Parenthood Federation of America Newsletter, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 10)
        - Pamphlets, 1939-44, undated (Box 26, Folder 11-12)
    - Publicity: lists, newspaper clippings, press releases, printed material, statements, and transcript of radio broadcast, 1940-46, undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Reports, 1941
        - General, 1941-43 (Box 26, Folder 14)
        - Clinical, 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 15)
        - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 16)
        - Distribution, [see oversize material, Box 37] (Box 26)
        - Interviewers reports by Mildred Delp, 1939-41 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Research: article abstracts, 1939-43 18-20 (Box 26, Folder 18-20)
    - Research: article abstracts, 1939-43 18-20 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
      - Subjects
        - Birth control legislation
          - International: lists and 4x6 card file, undated, [see box 27a for cards] (Box 27, Folder 4)
          - United States: chart, correspondence, drafts, notes, reports, and statements, 1939-40 (Box 27)
        - Population data
          - General: typescript of speech, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
          - Germany, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 6)
          - United States: charts and lists, 1939-40 (Box 27, Folder 7)
        - Quotations in support of birth control: lists, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
        - Miscellaneous material: lists and notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Planned Parenthood World Population
      - General: printed material, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Board of Directors: lists, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - "The Population Crisis: 20th Century Challenge" conference: position papers, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Annual reports, 1965-66 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1965-67 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Miscellaneous: correspondence, notes, and public statements, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Voluntary Parenthood League: printed material, 1921-24, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Other activities
    - Citizens Committee to Free Earl Browder: correspondence, and pamphlet, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Clifton's Food Service Training School: printed material, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - East and West Foundation
      - Correspondence, 1944-46, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Events: invitations, list, programs, and tickets, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Memoranda, 1944-45, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Notes, 1944, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Publicity: newsletters, newspaper clippings, and printed material, 1945, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Reports, 1944, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Meals for Millions
      - General 1945-1968, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence
        - Chamberlain, Ernest, 1955-67 (Box 28, Folder 10)
        - Clinton, Clifford, 1945-66 (Box 28, Folder 11-15)
        - Erby, Ellen B. and Nina Hard, 1950-65 (Box 28, Folder 16)
        - Ferguson, George, 1947-49 (Box 28, Folder 17)
        - Hopkins, Hazel, 1955-68 (Box 28, Folder 18)
        - Newcomb, Antoinette, 1948-50, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
        - Potter, Sue, 1947-68 (Box 28, Folder 20)
        - Stephens, Don, 1946, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
        - Tutak, Helen, 1955-67, undated (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Fundraising: correspondence, 1947-62, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Publicity
        - Newsletters, 1952-65 (Box 29, Folder 2)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1952-65 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Reports, 1948, undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - National Citizens Political Action Committee: newspaper clipping, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - National Council of Women: correspondence, 1949 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - National Recreation Association: correspondence, publicity, and reports, 1933, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - National Woman's Party: bulletins, correspondence, newsletters, newspaper clippings, and publicity, 1936-64 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Pathfinder Fund: printed material, 1965-66 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Rancho la Puerta: business cards, correspondence, lists, notes, photographs, pamphlets, postcards, printed material, and receipts, 1966, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Rosicrucian Society: correspondence, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Tucson Council of Social Agencies: correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, publicity, quotations, resolutions, and summaries, 1936-46, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Tucson Medical Center: correspondence, minutes, newsletter, and newspaper clippings, 1945-47 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - World Center for Women's Archives, Inc.: correspondence, lists, and printed material, 1939, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - World Food Congress: announcement, correspondence, and program, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 15)
- SERIES IV. SUBJECT FILES 1832-1968
  - Birth control movement
    - General: newspaper clippings, 1920-60 s, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 16-20)
    - History: typescripts and printed material, 1929-40 s (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Contraception
    - Effectiveness: reprinted articles, 1937-43 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - International status
      - Asia
        - General: printed material, 1933 and 1966 (Box 30, Folder 2)
        - China: newspaper clippings and printed material, 1928-31, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
        - India: newspaper clippings and printed material, 1927-30 (Box 30, Folder 4)
        - Japan: newspaper clippings, 1939-41 (Box 30, Folder 5)
        - Pakistan: newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 6)
        - Philippines: newspaper clippings, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Australia/New Zealand: printed material, 1927-43 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Europe
        - General: printed material, 1930-39 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Austria: newspaper clippings, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 10)
        - England: newspaper clippings, printed material, and typescript, 1930-44 (Box 30, Folder 11)
        - France: newspaper clippings, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 12)
        - Germany: typescript, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 13)
        - Italy: newspaper clippings, 1924-31, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
        - Scandinavia: newspaper clippings (in Scandinavian languages), 1934-41 (Box 30, Folder 15)
        - Spain: newspaper clippings, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 16)
        - Switzerland: printed material, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 17)
        - U.S.S.R.: printed material, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - North America
        - Mexico: printed material, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 19)
        - Puerto Rico: printed material, 1938-42 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Legal status
      - General: printed material and typescripts, 1921-44, undated (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - Hearings
        - Extract from hearings before the Committee on the Judiciary, House of Representatives, Seventy-third Congress, second session, on H.R. 5978, Serial 2, Jan 18-19, 1934 (Box 30, Folder 22)
        - Extract from hearings before the Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Seventy-first Congress, third session, on S. 4582, Feb13- 14, 1931 (Box 30)
        - Extracts from hearings before the Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Seventy-second Congress, first session, on S. 4436, May 12 and 20, 1932 (Box 30)
        - Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Seventy-second Congress, first session, on S. 4436, May 12, 19-20, 1932 (Box 30)
        - Extracts from Hearings before the Committee on Ways and Means, House of Representatives, Seventy-second Congress, first session, on H.R. 11082, May 19-20, 1932 (Box 30)
        - Extracts from Hearings before the Committee on Ways and Means, House of Representatives, Seventy-second Congress, first session, on H.R. 11082, May 19-20, 1932 (Box 30)
        - Extracts from Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Seventy-third Congress, second session, on S. 1842, Mar 1, 20, and 27, 1934 (Box 23)
        - Hearings before a Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, Seventy-third Congress, second session, on S. 1842, Mar. 1, 20, and 27, 1934 (Box 30, Folder 23)
        - Hearings before the Subcommittee No. 8 of the Committee on the Post Office and Post Roads, House of Representatives, Seventy-fourth Congress, first session, on H.R. 154, H.R. 3252, H.R. 5049, H.R. 5162, H.R. 5360, Mar. 8, 1935 and H.R. 5370 on Mar. 8, Apr. 4 and 10, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Medical indications: printed material, 1928-42 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Medical profession: printed material, 1930-66, undated (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Methods: printed material and typescript, 1926-67, undated (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
    - Planned pregnancies: printed material, 1932 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Public health: printed material, 1939-40 s, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Public opinion: printed material, 1936-43 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Quotations from supporters: printed material and typescripts, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Relief: printed material and typescripts, 1933-37 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Religion
      - General: printed material and typescript "Birth Control and the Bible" and "What the Bible Really Does Not Say About Birth Control," by May Bell Morgan, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Judaism: printed material, 1927 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Protestantism: printed material and typescripts, 1932-43, undated (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - Roman Catholicism: printed material and typescripts
        - 1923-42 (Box 31, Folder 11)
        - 1943-67, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Resources: printed material, 1940-41 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Eugenics: printed material, 1925-40 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Infertility and sterility: printed material, 1928-44 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Maternal health: printed material, 1933-39 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Mental health: printed material, 1933-53, undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Mortality rates (infant and maternal): printed material, 1925-39 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Population: printed material, 1832-1968 (Box 32, Folder 8-10)
  - "Portraits of Outstanding Americans of Negro Origin" exhibit: newspaper clippings, printed material, and photograph, 1944-48, 1967, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Population control: printed material, 1934-44 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Sanger, Margaret
    - Biographical material
      - Writings about Sanger
        - Autobiographical material: correspondence, drafts and notes, 1922-1930s (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Biographical sketches, 1920s-68, n.d (Box 33, Folder 2)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1933-67, undated (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
      - Interviews: printed material, questionnaire, and typed transcripts, 1935-57. n.d. (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Itineraries and travelogues, 1934-60 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Tributes: correspondence, nominations, printed material, speeches, and typescripts, 1931-1960s, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Funeral records: invitations and programs, 1966 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Photograph, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, [see also SERIES II. Correspondence - Individuals - Friends and associates - Sanger, Margaret]
      - 1917-32 (includes Charlotte Perkins Gilman) (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - 1933-35 (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
      - 1936 (Box 33, Folder 13-14)
      - 1937 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - 1938 (includes Wallis Windsor) (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
      - 1939 (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
      - 1940 (includes Carrie Chapman Catt) (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - 1941 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - 1942 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - 1943-48 (includes Pearl Buck) (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - 1949-65 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Speeches and articles: drafts, fragments, lists, manuscripts, notes, printed material and typescripts, circa 1910s-50 s, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Sanger documentary "The Margaret Sanger Story": correspondence, 1951-52 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Sanger manuscript collections
      - Library of Congress: catalogs, contracts, correspondence, legal documents, and lists, 1939-67, undated (Box 35, Folder 2-4)
      - New York Public Library: correspondence, 1938-64 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Sophia Smith Collection: correspondence, lists, memoranda, and typescripts, 1946-69 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Schwimmer, Rosika: biographical sketch, correspondence, and newspaper clipping, 1937-47 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Scott, Michael: photograph and press release, 1949-50 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Sex education: printed material, 1938-44 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Sterilization: correspondence and printed material, 1923-30 s, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Travelo-Address Book: correspondence, drafts, and printed material, 1941-42 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - World Population Conference: program and reprint, 1927-28 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - World War II: printed material, 1940s (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Yoga: printed material, undated (Box 35, Folder 14)